Guide to the R. L. (Robert Luther) Duffus Papers, 1903-1971
Department of Special Collections
R. L. (Robert Luther) Duffus Papers,
1903-1971
Special Collections M0302
Duffus, R. L. (Robert Luther), 1888-1972.
1.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Robert L. Duffus, 1975-1978, and Mrs. William Duffus, 1979.
Biographical Note
Robert Luther Duffus, a novelist with more than six published works, was born in Waterbury, Vermont, July 10, 1888 and received his A.B. from Stanford in 1910 and his A.M. in 1911. He worked for the San Francisco Bulletin (1911-1918), the San Francisco Call (1918-1919), the New York Globe (1919-1923), and the New York Times (1937-1971). He died November 28, 1972.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, clippings, photographs, certificates, and publications. Letters are primarily from Robert Duffus to his brother, William (1903-1969). Photographs are of Duffus at various times during his life, from high school graduation (1905) to a photograph taken in 1960.
Container List
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1903-09. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1910-12. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus. (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1913-19. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1920-29. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1930-39. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1943-50. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1950-59. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- R.L.D. to William Duffus, 1960-69. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Thorstein Veblen to Evelyn Wells, Dec. 5, 1920? (Box 1, Folder 13)
- R. L. D. to Evelyn Wells: 4 letters, 1948, 1968-69;1 letter re. incidents about Castro, Feb., 1944;R.L.D. to Evelyn Wells, May 1964, Oct. 1969;Poem The Unknown Soldier, New York Times, 1946. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence to Duffus, 1963, 65,66, 68-74. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Registration Certificates and Report Cards, 1907-11. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Honorable Mention, Prize Essay Contest on Patriotic Citizenship, 1906. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- L.L.D. Degree Citation, 1938. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Clippings by Duffus -- Sequoia, Chaparral. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Clippings by Duffus -- N.Y. Times, 1962,and S.F. Times, 1915. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newsclippings by, re. Duffus. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Williamstown and Waterbury, Vermont photos. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Publications (Box 2)
  - 1. LSJU Bulletin: Directory of Officers and Students; Feb. 1907, Oct. 1909, Feb. 1910, Winter 1918-19.
  - 2. Overland Monthly; Jan. 1905, March 1908, Sept. 1910, Oct. 1910, Jan. 1911.
  - 3. Stanford Alumnus; March 1915.
  - 4. The Chaparral; Nov. 1909, Jan 1910, Feb. 1910, Sept. 1910, March 1911.
  - 5. And a Note for N.Y. -- by Duffus; N.Y. Times Magazine.
  - 6. Lilian D. Wald: Brochure upon her installation into The American Hall of Fame, 1971
- Photographs
  - 1. H.S. Waterbury, Vt., 1905.
  - 2. N.Y. Times Studio, Spring 1943.
  - 3. Shiny. New York Times Studio, Jan. 1960.
  - 4. Globe (N.Y.) Editorial Staff, 1920.
  - 5. N.Y. Times Editorial Board, Nov. 1949.
  - 6. Carmel, Calif., 1914.
  - 7. Pictures of Vermont: Williamstown and Waterbury.
  - 8. R.L. Duffus; 1923, 1949.
  - 9. R.L.D.; 1927,New York City.
  - 10. R.L.D. at Cloisters, N.Y.C., 1961.
  - 11. R.L.D. at Cloisters, N.Y.C., 1961.
  - 12. Grocery Store, Mission City, B.C., Canada, 1942(editorial by R.L.D. in N.Y. Times).
  - 13. R.L.D.'s uncle and aunt, Lucius and Alice Cooley; his father and mother, John and Helen Graves Duffus; his brother, William McGlashan.
  - 14. R.L.D.'s parents, John and Helen Duffus; his brother William McGlashan.
  - 15. R.L.D. and Ed Morrow of N.Y. Times Bureau in Buenos Aires, Argentina, interviewing President Aramburu, Interpreter Ruby, May 1956.
  - 16. R.L.D. interviewing Pres. Aramburu, Interpreter Ruby. Buenos Aires, Argentina, May 1956.
  - 17. R.L.D., Pasadena, California, July 1911.
  - 18. R.L.D., Graduation from Waterbury, Vt. High School, June 1905.
  - 19. R.L.D., author of `The Sky But Not the Heart' -- 1936, cop.1.
  - 20. R.L.D., Montpelier, Vt., Sept. 1948.
  - 21. R.L.D., 1915.
  - 22. Caricature of R.L.D. by Charles Dunn of Nation's Business Magazine and description with quote; and caricature with signatures from S.F. Bulletin, Feb. 1914.
  - 23. R.L.D., author of `The Sky But Not the Heart' -- 1936,cop. 2&3.
  - 24. R.L.D. with Mr. and Mrs. W.L. Laurence, 1959.
  - 25. R.L.D. and L.L. D., Westport, Conn., 1936.
  - 26. R.L.D., Westport, Conn., railroad station, 1935.
  - 27. R.L.D., Pasadena, Calif., 1910.
  - 28. R.L.D., author of `Night Between the Rivers.'
  - 29. R.L.D., Westport, Conn.
  - 30. R.L.D. at Longman Green Publishers, 1930.
  - 31. R.L.D. at reception.
  - 32. R.L.D., 10 x 8 professional photo.
  - 33. R.L.D., Westport, Conn., near Compo Road, during WWII.
  - 34. R.L.D. on train for Calif., 1942.
  - 35. R.L.D. at award dinner, the Waldorf, 1950.
  - 36. The Times Forum, 1943;Henry Taylor; R.L.D.; Orville Prescott; Mr. Carlson.
  - 37. R.L.D. in study, Westport, Conn., 1928.
  - 38. R.L.D., Westport, Conn., 1954.
  - 39. R.L.D. with H.E. Armand and M. Berard, 1960.
  - 40. R.L.D., L.L.D., Patterson, and Myron Clement.
  - 41. Photo of portrait of R.L.D. by Lichtenauer, 1946.
  - 42. The Tower of Jewels; Panama `Pacific Exposition, 1915.
  - 43. Mr. and Mrs. Duffus, S.F., Panama- Pacific Exposition, 1915.
  - 44. R.L.D. at Carmel, Calif., August 1914.
  - 45. Photo of front page of the S.F. Bulletin, July 17, 1911;headline reads Fair Directors May Name Site Tonight.
  - 46. R.L.D., class of 1905,Waterbury.
  - 47. Williamstown, Vermont: Robert, William and Marjorie Duffus
- Gift of Mrs Robert L. Duffus, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1.)
  Addition to collection. Includes correspondence from:
  - Kreisler, Fritz 1917 Apr 11, TLS 1 p
  - Uppman, Theodor 1957 Mar 5, ALS 2 pp
  - [Gkubo, Mine] nd2 drawings with well wishes.
  - Keller, Helen nd, ALS 1 p
  - Davidson, Jo ndsketch of R.L. Duffus
  - Davidson, Mrs. Florence 1949 Apr 12, TLS 1p
  - Pentland, Lord 1946 Jan 17, ALS 1p
  - Wald, Lillian D., 1935 Nov 27; 1936 Jan 27; TLS 2 pp; TLS 1 p
    Also included are congratulatory letters, and letters of thanks.
- Gift of Mrs R L Duffus, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - MS Many Waters for English 22 [Stanford University] Feb 2, 1910.Ca 3800 words. [Page 10 and 11 missing]., 19 pp.
- Gift of Mrs R L Duffus, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notes on the Duffus family by Leah-Louise (Mrs RL) Duffus, Nov. 1975with corrections and suggestions from William M. Duffus, given by him in March 1947., Typescript xerox. 7 pp.
  - 31 letters to his younger sister, Marjorie Alice, and her husband, Sam Bryan. 1915 to 1970.
- Gift of Mrs Wm Duffus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Robert L. Duffus to his brother William, and his brother's wife, Ursula. 1911-1942.
- Gift of Mrs Wm Duffus, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Robert L. Duffus to his brother William and his brother's wife, Ursula. 1943-1968.